{
    "id": "60c6e872b63640fe8d3b20ec9067af1c",
    "title": "Little, Few, Likely",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Are you ………………………….. to be staying in this evening?",
            "description": "Be likely can be followed by a to-infinitive. Probable is not used in this way.",
            "answers": [
                "likely",
                "probable",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "5773959c437f4881af7cb87bed385d8b"
        },
        {
            "question": "It is likely …………………………….",
            "description": "When ‘it’ is the subject, be likely is usually followed by a that-clause.",
            "answers": [
                "for the meeting to be postponed",
                "that the meeting will be postponed",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "d33038c80f0f475780938462db34c915"
        },
        {
            "question": "……………………….. politicians are really honest.",
            "description": "We use few with plural nouns and little with uncountable nouns.",
            "answers": [
                "Few",
                "Little",
                "Less"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "979cadf3051b4b8fb7289fac8a3878d1"
        },
        {
            "question": "Could I try ……………………… soup?",
            "description": "Little has a rather negative meaning. A little is closer to some.",
            "answers": [
                "little",
                "a little",
                "few"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f9602ff5599f47a190783b26cd55ae2d"
        },
        {
            "question": "Only …………………………. my students like mathematics.",
            "description": "We use few of before a noun with a determiner.",
            "answers": [
                "a few",
                "a few of",
                "a little of"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "08c8c8c83bda4f38a7b44dc0bffb0571"
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………….. people can claim that they always tell the truth.",
            "description": "Before a noun without a determiner, we use few.",
            "answers": [
                "Few",
                "Few of",
                "Little",
                "Little of"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "278034b29fe34350b138f48fcf3ea3b2"
        },
        {
            "question": "…………………………. us can claim that we always tell the truth.",
            "description": "Before a pronoun we use few of.",
            "answers": [
                "Few",
                "Few of",
                "Little of"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "49c323cabcb64bd99bf224afef32643b"
        },
        {
            "question": "Could I have a …………………………. the soup?",
            "description": "Before a noun with a determiner, we use little of.",
            "answers": [
                "little more",
                "few more of",
                "little more of"
            ],
            "correct": 2,
            "id": "bda4356c36f04f0091d70f5eaf0678cc"
        },
        {
            "question": "You don’t need to go shopping. We have got …………………. bacon.",
            "description": "A little is similar to some. Little has a negative meaning. It means almost nothing.",
            "answers": [
                "little",
                "a little",
                "a few"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "f5366900190b41958d6fd20cd66e5095"
        },
        {
            "question": "The movie was ………………………… interesting",
            "description": "We cannot use little to modify other adjectives or adverbs.",
            "answers": [
                "not very",
                "little"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "6ecc17c2f46f4aaaa6c7143d88c96b24"
        },
        {
            "question": "She seldom stays ………………………",
            "description": "In questions and negatives we usually use long.",
            "answers": [
                "long",
                "for a long time",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0,
            "id": "81ef00dfda23464b87ae4bf64c30fd1a"
        },
        {
            "question": "We have been waiting ………………………..",
            "description": "In affirmative clauses, we usually prefer for a long time. ",
            "answers": [
                "long",
                "for a long time",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 1,
            "id": "dcd03a4eee8a4ce1bbd72de0b879c3ab"
        }
    ]
}